如果我吃点什么来催眠
If I take something to help me sleep,
明天开会就会昏昏沉沉的
I'll be groggy for the meeting.
但如果我什么也不吃  就睡不着
But if I don't take anything and I don't sleep,
明天开会还是会昏昏沉沉的
I'll be groggy for the meeting, you know?
我在再次竞选当地房地产经纪人团体的
I was up for re-election as social chair
联谊会主席
of our local realtors group.
今晚进行投票
The vote was tonight.
我超级紧张
I was so nervous,
基本没在听克莱尔为我鼓励
I could barely hear Claire's pep talk.
我为什么求米奇尔
Why did I beg Mitchell
介绍我认识这个开发商
to introduce me to this developer?
你说得对  我们很快就会知道了
You're right. We'll know soon enough.
我要上楼了  看看能不能睡着
I'm gonna go upstairs, see if I can get some sleep.
爱你
Love you.
我也希望这样
I hope so, too.
你好
Hello?
格尔
Hey, Gil.
没没没  你没吵醒我
No, no, no. You -- you didn't wake me.
你有听到什么消息吗
Um, so, you hear anything, or...
邓菲
Hey, Dunphy.
稍等我挂断这个蠢货的电话
Just wrapping up a phone call with this jackass.
我得挂了  邓菲
I got to run, Dunphy.
晚上得跟个蠢货见面
I got a late meeting with some jackass.
什么情  什么情况
What's going o-- what's going on?
大家都表态了  邓菲
The people have spoken, Dunphy.
我当选了  你出局了
I'm in. You're out.
很抱歉不得不私下告诉你
Sorry to have to tell you that in private.
票数接近吗
Was it even close?
不  我现在受命要做个工作
No! I have a mandate --
不是需要跟老婆隐瞒的那种
Not the kind you hide from your wife, either.
难以置信  我才任一届吗
I can't believe it. I'm a one-termer?
那我就跟亨利・尤斯塔斯・泰勒
That puts me alongside Henry Eustace Tyler
还有阿特・瓦格纳一样了
and Art Wagner!
从没见过阿特・瓦格纳
Never met Art Wagner.
"Gategate"事件后 他的经纪人执照被吊销了
They took away his realtor's license after Gategate.
别再追忆历史了  "蹬腿"
Okay, enough history, "Done-for."
快把东西交出来
Fork over the hardware.
格尔 正如我的前任对我说的那样
Gil, as my predecessor told me,
尊重办公室  尊重奖章
respect the office, respect the medallion.
真够闪的
Ooh, shiny.
你多长时间清理一次这玩意儿
How often do you clean this thing?
我每次洗澡的时候
Every time I shower.
别担心 晚上这奖章
Well, don't worry. It's gonna get a good buffing tonight
在我老婆脑后摇晃时就能好好磨光一下了
when it's swinging against the back of my wife's head.
这可不是尊重奖章的表现
That is not respecting the medall--
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
■
翻译：小饭  四方虾  王大可  罂粟无果  丁小七
时间轴：浓子   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
家  庭
摩  登
第五季 第十五集
等我们拿完我的过敏药
So, after we pick up my allergy medication,
你把我和曼尼载到博物馆
you drop Manny and I at the museum.
你为什么非得去
Why do you even have to go?
其他母亲也会参加这次活动
Ay, other mothers are going to the field trip, too.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不会缠着你
I'm not going to be all over you,
让你感觉压抑的
trying to suffocate you.
别那样说话
Don't talk like that.
我讨厌拥挤的电梯
I hate crowded elevators.
只有一件事更讨厌
Only one thing worse --
那就是电梯停了  你被困在里面
When they stop and you get trapped.
其实  还有一件事更讨厌
Actually, there's one thing even worse than that.
没关系  先生  不用怕
It's okay, sir. There's no need to panic.
跟他一起被困住
Getting trapped with him.
我不知道这家伙的名字
I don't even know the guy's name.
他跟我同个俱乐部的
He belongs to my club.
但不知道为什么
But for whatever reason,
他总是有办法
he has the knack for showing up
在我最糟糕的时候出现
when I'm at my absolute worst.
马上回来
Be right back.
[撅起嘴来]
来  我来帮你
Here, let me help you.
也许我们该帮帮别人
Maybe we should help someone else.
别害怕
Oh, don't be frightened.
跨大步
Big step!
谁是下一个
Who's next?
抱歉  胡娇要给你们的婚礼找什么
I'm sorry. Pepper's getting a what for your wedding?
一名摄指
A D.P.
不是
No!
不  是摄影指导
No, a director of photography.
显然  他是个大咖
Yeah, apparently, he's a big deal.
他获得过金球奖
He won a Golden Globe.
不  奥斯卡是靠实力赢的
No, you win an Oscar.
金球奖是花钱买的
You buy a Golden Globe.
他只能今早跟我们见面
So he can only meet with us this morning.
你今天能去学校接莉莉吗
Is -- is there any way you could pick Lily up from school?
行啊  行  没问题
Uh, yeah. Yeah, I can.
我会  我会带她去公园  很好
I'll -- I-I'll take her to the park. That's good.
这样我就不会去想跟你朋友见面的事了
It'll get my mind off this meeting with your friend.
我好紧张
I am so nervous.
我很久没开过销售会议了
I haven't had a sales meeting in...forever.
现在有点迟钝了
I'm a little rusty.
你还记得我们以前总叫你小迟钝吗
Do you remember when we used to call you "Little rusty"?
我那时才8岁
I was 8,
现在我还是可以取消这次会面
and I can still cancel this meeting.
好吧  我得挂了  我得
Fine. I got to go. I got to --
我不知道我得干什么
I don't know what I have to do.
这是干什么
What is this?
我在为了我的摔跤比赛流汗减重
I'm sweating off weight for my wrestling match.
我就是穿这个睡觉的
I slept in this.
这就是为什么我们找不到塑料包装用吗
Does this have anything to do with why we're out of plastic wrap?
那是最里面一层
Oh, it's the bottom layer.
而且我告诉你吧
And I've got some news for you --
那东西并不能让我保持新鲜
It's not keeping me fresh.
好吧  你要迟到了
Okay. Um, you're gonna be late.
你在后座脱衣服吧
You got to get undressed in the backseat.
要给他什么指示吗
Ooh, got any pointers for him?
你们非得现在搬这个吗
Do you girls have to move that now?
我最近感觉很孤单
Well, I've been lonely.
屋子放面镜子会让我感觉有个伴
Having a mirror in my room will be like having company!
你女儿真是只害怕孤独的小鹦鹉
Ugh, your daughter's a parakeet.
小心点
Careful.
别再说了  我知道我在
Stop saying that. I think I know what I'm --
等一下
Oh, one second.
-天啊  -你好
- Oh, my God.  - Hello!
不会  现在正合适
No, this is a good time.
-海莉  -好了  天啊
- Haley!  - All right. Geez!
没事  我在帮我妹妹做点事儿
No, I just got to help my sister out with something.
再见
Okay. Bye.
我们把这个放下一会儿
Okay, let's just put this down for a second.
天啊
Oh, my God.
-怎么了  -恐怕这面镜子放不下
- What?  - I don't think this is gonna fit.
你得找一面小点的镜子
You'll have to get a smaller mirror.
天啊  天啊  天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
海莉  换面镜子你身材又不会变
Haley, you'll still be the same size in it.
不
No!
天呐  我们被困住了
Oh, my God! We're trapped!
这  这  这没什么大不了的
Well, it -- it's -- it's not such a huge disaster.
只是你上学会迟到一会儿而已
You know, you'll just be a little late for school.
再好好想想  到底是哪样
Make up your mind! Which is it?!
天呐  我错过了一条短信
Oh, my god. I'm missing a text.
来真的了  是不是
Just got real, didn't it?
谁派你来的
Who sent you?!
快点  我们得走了  可不能迟到
Come on. We have to go. We can't be late.
我太激动了  你呢
I am so excited. Aren't you?
-不是吧  -什么  怎么了
- Oh, no. - What? What's happening?
又要搞砸吗
How are you ruining this?
莉莉的班上有虱子
There's a report of lice in Lily's class.
估计是从波西亚那传来的
Ugh. It's probably from Portia.
她总是特别脏
You know, she is always so filthy.
他们不跟她一起游泳了
They had to kick her out of swim buddies
因为她有次落了个游泳圈在泳池周围
because she left a ring around the pool.
我们大概应该取消会议
We should probably cancel our meeting
亲自去接莉莉
and pick Lily up ourselves, huh?
不是大概  是必须
Probably? We have to!
我们不能为了
We can't risk infecting Claire
和全国最棒的婚礼摄影师见面
just so we can keep a meeting
就让克莱尔有被传染虱子的风险
with the top wedding photographer in the state.
不  不
No. No.
我这就打给她
I am calling her.
没错  这就对了
Yeah, it's the right thing to do...
即使基本没可能
...even though it's like a 1% chance
会传染给她
of her actually catching anything
倒是很可能吓死她
and a 100% chance of us freaking her out.
别  等等
Well, now, wait.
我们是不是有点自私  小卡
Are we being selfish here, Cam?
也许  说下去
Maybe. Go on.
要是我们提醒她
Well, if-- if we alarm her just so
只是为了不让自己良心不安
that we can have a clear conscience,
会不会显得我们太
doesn't that make us...
-冷酷  -冷酷
- Monsters.   - ...monsters.
我们何不帮她个忙
Wouldn't we be doing her a favor
就不告诉她  省得她担心呢
by not telling her and sparing her all that worry?
今天帮她的第二个大忙
Second huge favor of the day,
你还帮她约了你的客户和她见面
after you got her a meeting with your client.
我有点负罪感
Mm. I'm -- I'm starting to feel bad about this.
怎么了  因为我们帮了她太多忙
What, because we're doing so many favors,
可克莱尔却报答不了吗
Claire will never be able to pay us back?
谢谢
Thank you.
好  就不给她添加压力了  小卡
Nope, she does not need the stress, Cam.
好的  就这样  不再帮克莱尔了
Yep. That's it. No more favors for Claire.
不帮了
No!
看我们
Look at us!
两个金发女郎  真开心
Two blondes, having fun!
伙计
Hey, buddy!
比赛快开始了
My match is coming up.
有什么最后的"父建"
Got any final dad-vice?
这个词开始听习惯了吧
Starting to sound natural, right?
没别的  去好好享受比赛就好了
You know what? Just get out there and enjoy yourself.
你尝试了一项新的运动  很棒
You showed real character trying a new sport.
不管结果如何  我都为你骄傲
No matter what happens, I couldn't be prouder.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, dad.
加油  打败他们
You bet. Go get 'em!
这可能是当家长最棒的一件事
That may be the best part about being a parent.
不管你自己的生活如何
Whatever's going on in your personal life,
你的孩子高兴  你也会高兴
when your kid's happy, you're happy.
一个开心的孩子就像抗抑郁药
A happy kid is like an antidepressant,
而且是纯天然的
but a natural one,
不是需要背着老公藏在
not the kind your husband has to find
首饰盒里的那种
in your jewelry drawer.
说多了
Enough said about that!
格尔你好
Hey, Gil.
真抱歉啊
Oh, whoops! I'm sorry, man.
希望没晃瞎你眼睛
I hope I didn't blind ya.
尽管你可能不会想看接下来的画面
Although you might not want to see what's next.
我们的孩子要比赛摔跤
Our kids are wrestling each other.
-你在开玩笑吧  -没有
- Are you kidding?   - Nope!
那个就是我的小选手
There's my little bra-snapper right there.
他可是很生猛的
He's a beast, man.
是啊是啊
No, uh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
我明白
No, I get it.
你想吓唬我
This is when you try to intimidate me.
不不  祝你好运
No! No. Hey, good luck.
你听没听说过
Hey, did you ever hear about those
边境那些非法的童子摔跤比赛
illegal baby-fighting rings they got in the border?
那都是假的
That's not a real thing.
我和我太太带他去参加过
Yeah, wife and I brought him down there.
赢了一整车鸡回来
Won a whole carload of chickens.
回头见了伙计
See you out there, man.
那根本没有的事
That never happened!
注意  注意
Watch yourself! Watch yourself!
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
不需要了  你很努力了
No need. You worked hard.
我只希望你开心就好
I just want you to have fun.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, dad.
另外我还想修正一下
Also, I'd like to revise
我在车上跟你说的咬人的事
what I said to you in the car about biting.
曼尼  这里什么都有
Manny, they have everything here--
雨林体验  飓风室
the rainforest experience, the hurricane booth,
人体解析
discovering the body --
这个哥伦比亚也有  只是
We have that one in Colombia, too, but --
形式不同
but a different kind.
-不  -怎么了
- Oh, no.  - What?
你没听到吗
You don't hear that?
是我的新鞋  吱吱响
It's my new shoes. They're squeaking.
那就轻点走
Then walk softer.
完了
Oh, great.
地板就像猫玩具做的
It sounds like the floor's made of cat toys.
-我完了  -为什么
- I'm screwed!  - Why?
为什么  因为这些孩子会取笑任何事
Why? Because these kids make fun of everything.
让他们揪着这事  我会永世不得脱身
Hand them this, it'll stick with me forever.
咕哝就是这样
That's what happened to mumbles.
曼尼  来跟我们走
Hey, Manny, come with us.
走吧  咕哝
Let's go, mumbles.
就那一次
One time!
走吧
Let's go.
我不去了
Just go on without me.
我就在这站着吧
I'm just gonna stand here.
永远站着吗
What -- forever?
他这是怎么了
What happened to him?
上高中前  他没有这么强烈的
He didn't used to be that self-conscious
自我意识
before high school.
他以前就披着斗篷
He used to go around in his poncho,
吹着排箫
play the pan flute.
真想念我的小曼尼
Ay, I miss my little old Manny.
曼尼  你太在意别人怎么想了
Manny, you care too much about what other people think!
我知道这里有些母亲
I know that some of the mothers here
也想取笑我
want to make fun of me
因为我有口音和有弹性的胸部
because of my accent and my bouncy bosom.
可她们没有  知道为什么吗
But they don't. You know why?
因为我不在乎  因为我充满自信
Because I don't care. Because I walk with confidence.
你也可以  我们走
And so can you. Let's go.
这地方真差劲
This place sucks so bad.
可不是么  咯咯笑
Sure does, giggles.
我就那么笑了一次
One time!
好吧  她还没走
Okay, she's not leaving.
你得把她从楼梯上引开
You got to lure her away from the staircase.
她肯定相信你
She'll trust you.
你穿得像个驯兽员
You're kind of dressed like an animal trainer.
你为什么一直觉得它是母的
Why do you keep calling it a "She"?
因为公的不会那样看我
Well, because "He"s don't look at me like that.
天啊  她打算睡上一整天吗
My god, is she gonna sleep all day long?
真的吗  你还嫌人家睡得多
Okay, that, coming from you?
那负鼠肯定乐坏了
The possum's actually laughing.
而且  它显然没在睡觉
And, besides, I mean, it's obviously not sleeping.
她还能干什么
What else would she be doing?
装[玩]...
Playing...?
玩...什么
Playing...what?
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
[Playing possum 俗语: 装死,装睡;装傻]
装死  人人都知道
Playing possum, the one thing
这是负鼠最擅长干的事
that absolutely everyone knows possums do.
骗到你了
Ha, ha! I got you!
我像负鼠那样跟你装傻呢  我假装
I was playing possum on you by pretending --
不  别糊弄我  想都不要想
Yeah, no, no, no, no, no. Don't even.
不  上帝啊
No, my god.
妈妈要到5点才能回家
Mom's not even here until 5:00.
你还把唯一一个能量棒给吃了
And you ate our only power bar.
可能就是那个把它吸引来的
Well, that's probably what attracted it!
我们得朝它扔点儿什么
You know, we got to throw something at it.
好吧
Fine.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?!
博洛先生马上就来见您
Mr. Perlowe will be right with you.
-谢谢  -谢谢你
- Thank you. - Thank you.
我之前特别紧张  不过我觉得我能搞定
I was so nervous before, but I think I really got this.
不是吧
Oh, no!
什么  怎么了
What? What's happening?
又要搞砸吗
How are you ruining this?
为什么每个人都这么说我
Why does everybody say that?
那个  我们今早见的
The -- the director of photography
摄像指导拒绝了我们
we met with this morning --he's turning us down.
为什么
Why?
创意分歧
"Creative differences."
他建议我们其中一人在襟花上
He suggested one of us wear a hidden camera
装个隐藏相机
in our boutonniere.
[模仿著名电影A Room With A View: 看得见风景的房间]
他管这个叫"看得见风景的新郎"
He called it "Groom with a view."
某人却想把它叫做"小卡摄影"
Somebody got it into his head to call it the "Cam-cam."
于是就有了各种跳脚
Then there was a lot of foot-stomping
折手杖  摔单眼镜
and cane-snapping and monocle-smashing.
你们的婚礼摄影师是谁  小花生先生吗
Who is your wedding photographer -- Mr. Peanut?
[Mr. Peanut: 拿手杖戴单片眼镜的卡通形象]
他是指导
It's a director of --
-婚礼而已  -抱歉我迟到了
- It's a wedding. - Sorry I'm late.
吉姆・博洛
Jim Perlowe,
这是我姐姐  克莱尔・邓菲
this is my sister, Claire Dunphy.
你好  很高兴见到你
Hi. A pleasure to meet you.
我今天早上路过工地了
Listen, I went by the construction site this morning,
那些公寓肯定会建得非常棒
and those condos are gonna be fantastic --
当然  前提是要有好的衣柜和百叶窗
Assuming, of course, you get the right closets and blinds.
看来会议已经开始了  那么  好吧
Of cour-- appears the meeting has already started, so, okay!
是的开始了  再见  米奇尔
Yes, it has! Bye-bye, Mitchell!
-我们继续吗  -是的  当然
- Shall we?  - Yes, absolutely! So...
你好啊小懒虫
Hey, sleepy!
今天午睡得真久
Long nap today.
你和克莱尔肯定在公园玩得很累吧
Claire must've really worn you out at the park, huh?
是的
Yeah.
你想和我一起躺着吗  大爸
Do you want to lie down with me, daddy?
亲爱的  我拒绝这个要求的那一天
Oh, honey, the day I answer no to that question...
就是今天
...is today.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
我打电话给二爸
I got to call daddy.
你应该知道我们的优势不仅在于
You should know that it's not just our low prices
价格低廉
that set us apart.
我们还有丰富的经验
It's our level of experience.
我以前见过
You know,I have seen it before
一个新手走进一个不规则空间
a new guy walks into an irregular-shaped space,
他会说  我们应该从哪开始呢
and he's just like, "Ugh! Where do we even start?"
从测量开始  也许
You start with measurements, maybe.
喂  小卡  什么事
Hey, Cam, what's up?
正式确认某人头上有虱子了
Well, it's official. Someone has lice.
大爸  抱抱我
Daddy, hug me!
我也想啊  但是要记得这块地毯是岩浆
I would, but remember, the carpet's hot lava!
是的  热的岩浆
Yeah, hot lava!
天啊  你确定吗
Oh, my god. Are you sure?
确定
I think so.
她的脑袋跟跳跳糖一样噼啪响
Her head sounds like pop rocks.
你得警告克莱尔
You have to warn Claire.
大爸  这个游戏不好玩
Daddy, this game is mean.
你知道吗  亲爱的
Well, you know what, sweetie?
好吧  不  保持镇定
All right. No. J-just stay calm.
首先 如果你需要我做什么
First of all, if there's anything that you need from me,
不管是什么
anything at all,
我就住在使馆套房
I will be living at the embassy suites.
其次  她也不一定
Secondly, there's -- there's no guarantee
会被传染上
that she has it.
我现在就和她在一起
I mean, I'm with her right now.
如果她有虱子我会知道的
I think I'd know.
好吧  我想我知道了
Yeah, I think I know.
所以  像你看到的  这些都是模板
So, as you can see, all of them are modules,
他们可以根据各个房间而定制  米奇尔
So they can be customized for each unit -- Mitchell!
你们好啊
Hey! Hi!
那个  克莱尔  我需要跟你谈谈
So, claire, I need to talk to you.
是  好  等我们谈完的
Yeah, right -- right when we're done.
等开完会之后
Just after the meeting.
- 我们有松木  杉木   - 这事很重要
- We got pine, cedar...   - It's kind of important.
事实上  我得接这个电话
A-actually, I got to take this call.
-抱歉  -好的
- Excuse me.  - Okay.
你怎么了
What is going on with you?
是这样  你发现你一直在挠头了吧
Okay, so, you know how you've been scratching your head?
我的天  有这么明显吗
Oh, god. Is it that noticeable?
我有点儿神经性痉挛
I-I have some kind of nervous tic.
是  可能也有这个原因
Yeah, there might be one of those in there, too.
那个  莉莉在学校染上虱子了
Um, so, lily brought home lice from school.
什么
What?
是的  事实上  我本来想告诉你的
Yeah, and, actually, I would've told you,
但小卡觉得也许
but Cam thought that maybe --
你让我顶着
You let me walk around
啃我脑壳的虫子走来走去
with insects gnawing on my skull,
竟然不告诉我吗
and you said nothing?
是  但是克莱尔
Yeah, but, Claire --
给我过来  小迟钝
Come here, little rusty.
不  你听我说
No, listen, you --
什么样的禽兽为了自身利益
What kind of monster puts their self-interest
而不告诉另一个人
ahead of telling another human being
他们会被传染寄生虫
that they are going to get a parasite infestation?
我觉得你会做同样的事
I feel you would've done the same thing.
-绝不会  -不  克莱尔  住手
- Never.   - No, Claire, stop it!
我得出发去开另一个会了
Uh, I got to get off to another meeting.
克莱尔  我们别绕圈子了
But, Claire, let's just cut to the chase.
这件事就交给你
You got my business.
真是太棒了
Oh, super!
只是握手显然不够诚意吧
Oh, I think we're way past handshakes, huh?
[洛杉矶自然历史博物馆]
曼尼  给你的祖先们一点敬意
Manny, stop disrespecting your ancestors.
他们花了650万年才学会直立行走
It took them 6 1/2 million years to walk upright!
你没听导览的介绍吗
Didn't you hear the tour guy?
当然
"Duh."
别给我摆这种脸色
No, don't give me that attitude.
没有  我  你的脸怎么红了
No, I -- why is your face red?
什么
What?
肯定是我的抗过敏药
It must be my allergy medication.
我一定是对药物有过敏反应
I must be overreacting to it!
我帮你拿点水吧
Um, I'll get you some water.
那边就有个饮水机
There's a fountain right over there.
曼尼  你一整天都跑哪儿去了
Manny, where have you been all day?
我一直在"翼展"区
I was in the bird wing.
这名字起得真不错  对吧
Hilarious they call it that, no?
你妈妈呢
Where's your mom?
她刚刚还在这儿
She was just there.
她肯定藏起来了
I think she's hiding.
她应该是看到我跟她撞衫了
She probably saw she and I were wearing the same outfit
怕被我比下去  一直都这样
and didn't want to get outdone...as usual.
也许吧
Uh yeah, maybe.
最重要的是我
But the important thing
能够享受这个过程  对吧
is that I have fun out there, right?
我们再重复一遍
Okay, let's go over this again,
因为我觉得你没懂我的意思
'cause I feel like you're not listening.
你必须给我赢
I need you to win.
杰  你来了
Hey, Jay.
卢克
Hey, Luke.
别听你爸的
Don't let your dad get in your head.
尽力就行了
Get out there and do your best.
没问题
All right.
你到底在想什么
What the hell was that?
他的对手是格尔・索普的儿子
He's wrestling Gil Thorpe's kid.
我恨死那家伙了
I hate that guy.
总是想方设法让我自惭形秽
Always trying to make me feel like less of a man.
是拿走你的项链的那个家伙吗
The guy that took your necklace, right?
-那是我的奖牌  -随便你怎么叫
- My medallion! - Call it what you want.
我只是很高兴不用再帮你戴上它了
I'm just glad I don't have to help you with the clasp again.
杰  你在哭吗
Jay, are you crying?
当然不是
No!
裁判在座位区喷了消毒剂
Referee sprayed some disinfectant on the mats.
我弄到眼睛里了  你有纸巾吗
I got some in my eye. You got a tissue?
给你
Here you go.
送你了
Keep it.
那是我老婆的
It's my wife's.
-老爸  -儿子
- Hey, dad! - Hey, son!
你能来真好
Good to see you.
比赛快要开始了
Uh, the match is about to start... yeah?
也就是说  快要结束了
...which means it's about to finish.
他的对手看起来像棵矮牵牛花
You see that little petunia he's wrestling?
没错
Yes.
你认识格尔他爸吗
You know Gil's dad?
他总能看到我最糟糕的时刻
I know he always sees me at my worst.
这比赛一定要赢  菲尔
I really want this win, Phil.
非常非常想
I can taste it, like metal.
我也一样
Me, too. Metal.
我也搞不懂为什么
I don't know what it is with this guy,
但是不管我怎么做
but no matter what I do,
我就是赢不了他
I just can't win with him.
我跟他儿子也是这样的
That's the way I am with his son.
还有跟时代华纳电视公司打交道的时候
And Time Warner Cable.
感觉像被阉了一样憋屈
It's emasculating, you know?
这不是一个男人应该有的感觉
I mean, it's not a feeling a man should have.
杰  你知道爱的开头是什么吗
Jay, you know what the beginning of "Love" is?
上帝啊  我们只不过随便聊聊
Oh, for god's sake, we're just talking here.
为什么你总是要
Why do you always have to make everything
上纲上线
bigger than it is?!
你好[LO与Hello音似]
L.O.
菲尔  听我说
Hey, Phil, listen.
你的药店有卖治虱子的洗发水吗
Does your pharmacy carry lice shampoo?
莉莉在学校被传染了虱子
Lily got it at school.
走开  吓人的机器人
Ooh, away, scary robot!
走开
Away!
我不能呼吸了
I can't breathe.
很好  你头上的虫子也不能
Well, good. Neither can your hair pets.
-什么  -没事
- What?   - Nothing.
莉莉从什么人身上传染了虱子
Lily got lice from someone.
-肯定是波西亚  -还能是谁
- Portia. - Who else?
别去什么药店了
You know what? Skip the pharmacy.
我们那儿有治虱子的东西
Just -- just borrow our lice kit.
在地下室  钥匙在地毯下面
It's in the basement. The key's under the mat.
谢谢你  菲尔  谢谢
Thank you, Phil. Thanks.
好了
All right!
可以了  吓人的机器人
Enough.. with scary robot!
谁想扮成一只坐在车上的狗狗
But who wants to pretend to be a dog and ride in the car?
我
I do!
很好  我们门口见
Okay! Meet you at the door!
记着
And remember --
我们要把头伸出车窗外
we're gonna keep our head outside the window.
-真有趣  -是啊  真有趣
- Fun! - Yeah, fun! Uh-huh!
真是有趣
Fun.
好了  比赛开始了
All right, the match is starting.
我感觉到对胜利的渴望了
I feel that metal now in my mouth,
就像你之前说的一样
like you were saying.
万一他输了怎么办
What if he loses?
那也不要表现出失望
Then we hide our disappointment.
跟我学学  我都装了好多年了
Follow my lead. I've been doing it for years.
孩子需要知道我们永远无条件支持他
The kid needs to know we support him no matter what.
-加油卢克  -卢克加油
- Come on, Luke! - Luke!
[洛杉矶自然历史博物馆]
好了  他们走了
All right. They're gone.
好  我们赶紧走吧
Okay. Let's get out of here.
靠我近点
Stay close.
妈  你简直不可理喻[无与伦比]
Mom, you're unbelievable.
你真会说话  不过我知道我看起来很糟
Ay, that's sweet, but I know I look terrible.
你责备我自我意识太强
You come down on me for being self-conscious,
结果你自己因为脸变红了就躲起来
then you run and hide because your face is red.
你说得没错
You're right.
我一直怪其他高中生
I keep blaming the high-school boys
老是害你难为情
for making you self-conscious,
没想到是我造成的
and you're taking after me.
等我们躲到安全的地方之后
We can assign blame when we're safely
再互相指责吧
behind our tinted windows.
-我们被包围了  -才不是呢
- We're trapped! - No.
当我在洞穴人展区的时候
When I was in the caveman exhibit,
我发现了防火出口
I discovered fire exits.
上车以后我再跟你解释好笑在哪里
I'll explain to you why that's funny in the car.
跟我来
Follow me.
不行  曼尼
No, Manny.
是时候给你树立一个好榜样了
It's time for me to set a good example for you.
好吧
Okay.
妈  你要干嘛
Mom, what are you doing?
我要证明给你看别人的想法
I'm gonna show you that it's not important
并不重要
what other people think.
重要的是要坚持自我
What is important is that you stay true to yourself.
那是我妈妈做过最勇敢的事
It was the bravest thing my mom had ever done.
大家好
Hey, everybody!
听到我这个吱吱叫的鞋子了吗
Uh, hear my squeaky shoes?
太逗了  不是吗
Pretty funny, isn't it?
是啊  就是我  吱吱鞋
That's right, it's me -- ol' squeaky shoes.
太疯狂了
Crazy!
瞧瞧他那件粉衬衣
Get a load of that pink shirt.
真是太漂亮了
Aww, it's so pretty.
曼尼  上衣很美啊
Hey, Manny, nice top.
但你看我的鞋
Uh, but my shoes!
鞋怎么了  小粉红
What about 'em, pink top?
那是他做过最勇敢的事情
It was the bravest thing he has ever done.
他们叫我小粉红
They call me "Pink top."
我的英雄
My hero.
小粉红
Pink top.
比赛太棒了
Hey! Whoo! Good fight!
今天我们搞砸了卢克的比赛
We really blew it with Luke today.
我怎么可以那样做呢
How could I do that?
我父亲从来不错过任何机会让我知道
My dad never missed an opportunity to let me know
我让他失望了  我也这么对待我的外孙
when I disappointed him, and I do it to my grandkid.
我也做得不对
It's just as much my fault.
在我妻子身上  我清晰地看见了
I've seen what having a disapproving father
一个不认同她的父亲的危害
has done to my wife.
我应该做得更好的
I should've known better.
该死
Dang it.
伙计  我知道你不开心
Buddy, I know you're upset.
你绝对有权利那样
You've got every right.
我们把自己的争执发泄到摔跤比赛上
We made that wrestling match all about our stupid feud.
那是不对的
That was wrong.
忘了那些人渣吧
Forget about those jerks.
我们对你的感觉只有自豪
We couldn't be anything but proud of you,
就好像我特别为你妈妈感到自豪一样
just like I'm super proud of your mom.
我们先处理眼前这个问题吧
Let's repair this one first.
我们只是不想让你因为输了比赛
We just don't want you to beat yourself up
而感到自责
because you lost.
我没有
I'm not.
我刚开始学习摔跤不久
I just started wrestling.
当然  能赢固然好  但我尽力了
Sure, it would've been nice to win, but I tried my best.
我刚刚说"该死"  是因为忘了拿吸管
I just said "Dang it" Because I forgot to get a straw.
臭小子  他竟然没事
Son of a gun! He's actually okay.
我才不信
I don't buy it.
为什么  何出此言
Why? What are you talking about?
没有孩子可以在让父亲和外公失望后
No kid lets down his father and grandfather
还那么镇定自若
and is that okay with it.
他在掩藏情绪
He's burying his feelings.
也许他只是家教比较好
Or maybe he's just raised better than that.
他知道参与别人的战争是没有意义的
He knows it's pointless to fight other people's battles.
这是基因里带的  菲尔
It's all in the DNA, Phil.
我的老爹跟别人有矛盾的时候
My old man has a problem with somebody?
相信我
Trust me
我就在操场上找那个家伙的孩子了
I'm looking for that guy's kid on the schoolyard.
这是男人的处事方式
It's how men work.
曾经的处事方式
Or used to work.
也许那些嗜血的普里契特基因
Maybe those thuggish Pritchett genes
混合了一些更先进的邓菲基因
got mixed with more evolved Dunphy genes,
塑造了一个有着更高尚情操的人类
resulting in a more elevated human being.
天哪  他在攻击他
Oh, my god! He's attacking him!
放开我的孩子
Hey! Hey! Get off my kid!
你才要放开我的孩子
Hey. Hey! Get off my kid!
是你要放开我的孩子
Aah! You get off of my kid!
放开我女儿的老公
Hey, hey! Get off my daughter's husband!
管我叫你的孩子会死吗  杰
Would it kill you to call me your kid, Jay?
天哪  原来他在救他
Oh, my god. He was saving him.
祝你有愉快的一天
Oh. Have a good day.
结果好  一切好
Well...all's well that ends well.
是啊  我们走吧
Yeah, yeah. Here we go.
坐一下  孩子
Grab a seat, son.
-走吧  -这就来
- Move. - Coming in.
我想  还是来个普通汉堡吧
I think, uh, probably just a regular burger.
我看不到它了  你觉得它走了吗
I can't see it anymore. You think it's gone?
可能藏起来了
It could be hiding.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
你要干什么
What are you doing?!
我准备分散它的注意力
I'm gonna create a distraction
这样我们可以趁机跑出去
so that we can make a break for it.
给点时间预热
Give it a second to warm up.
好的
Okay.
它回来了
It's back!
我的天哪
Oh, my gosh.
这下面太黑了
It's so dark down here.
小心点  宝贝
Be careful, sweetie.
这下面是怎么了
What is going on down here?!
好吧  我不得不承认
All right, I got to admit something right here.
今天你让我很受感动  卢克
You impressed me today, Luke.
那个孩子刚刚噎住了
That kid started choking.
你眼里看到的不是竞争对手
You didn't see a rival or...
或是一个为自己家族而战的机会
...a chance to fight your family's stupid battles.
你看到的是一个需要帮助的人
You just saw somebody who needed help.
这让你成为了这辆车上最成熟的人
And that makes you the biggest man in this whole car.
你刚刚就是想攻击他  对不对
You just attacked him, didn't you?
他表现得像噎住了
He made that choke sign.
我以为他在嘲笑我刚才的比赛
I thought he was mocking my wrestling.
-这事我们自己知道就可以了  -是的
- Let's go ahead and keep that to ourselves. - Yeah.
我来开吧
I'll get it.
亲爱的  我收回之前所说的
Honey, I take back everything I ever said
所有关于这个发明的评价
about this stupid invention.
它有名字的
It has a name
注册商标  "真感觉挠头器"
"The real head scratcher, T.M."
请进
Well, come on in.
就是想跟你道个歉  小邓子
Just want to say I'm sorry, "Doofy."
那你还叫我
And yet you're still call--
今天你孩子的所作所为太棒了
What your kid did today was amazing.
你不会记恨我的  对吧
No hard feelings, right?
小卡  手头上的事情先停一下
Hey, Cam, hold off on that thing for a second.
莉莉  亲爱的
Lily, honey?
你开玩笑吗  一切都好
Are you kidding me? It's all in good fun.
那就好
All right. Good.
这个小可爱是谁啊
Whoa! Who's this little dumpling?
是我的侄女
Only my niece.
她最爱别人把她背在背上
If there's one thing she loves, it's piggy-back.
我没有啊
No, I don't.
有  快上来
Yep! Hop on up there!
好吧
All right!
这人是谁
Who's this man?
你可以叫我格尔叔叔
You can call me uncle Gil!
格尔叔叔
Uncle Gil!
你们两个看起来很和谐
You two look great together!
抱好了  对了
Get in there! Yeah!
我跟你说  这些小家伙最喜欢我了
I'm telling you, these little buggers love me.
要的就是这个效果
That's the plan! Yeah!